Portfolio: https://bthalpin.com | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/brian-halpin | GitHub: https://github.com/bthalpin

I am a full stack software developer specializing in MERN stack. Since the moment I was exposed to programming, it was all I ever wanted to do. I have always had a passion for problem solving, but thought my love of logic puzzles would be something I would only ever do as a hobby. Software development has given me an avenue to not only do what I love, but also to engage me and challenge me to always improve my skills.

SKILLS

Frontend: HTML5, CSS, jQuery, JavaScript, ReactJS, Bootstrap, Bulma

Backend: MySQL, Postgres, Express, Node, Python, Django

CREDENTIALS

Rutgers Coding Bootcamp – May 2022

CompTIA A+ Certification - December 2017

B.S. - Mechanical Engineering - Rutgers University, School of Engineering (New Brunswick, NJ) - May 2003

RELATED EXPERIENCE

RUTGERS CODING BOOTCAMP

Feb 2022 - May 2022

WHAT MOVIE WAS THAT?

https://bthalpin.github.io/What-Movie-Was-That | https://github.com/bthalpin/What-Movie-Was-That

JavaScript Developer

- An app that connects with a OMDB and YouTube APIs to provide the user with up to date movie information and trailers without ever having to leave the app.
- Collaborated with a skilled team using GitFlow to produce a polished web app. I was in charge of fetching and data from OMDB and YouTube API, using logic to manipulated the data, and updating the page with the appropriate information for the user.
 - Tools/Languages: HTML, CSS, Bulma JavaScript, OMDB API, YouTube API, and Git

CODE OUIZ

https://github.com/bthalpin/Code-Quiz | https://bthalpin.github.io/Code-Quiz/

JavaScript Developer

- A quiz app that randomly selects a number of question for the user to answer before the time runs out.
- As sole software developer for the project I organized the code in a modular code structure so that it can be easily expanded on to make a more robust quiz app with user generated questions.
 - Tools/Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and Git

WEATHER FORECAST

https://github.com/bthalpin/Weather-Forecast | https://bthalpin.github.io/Weather-Forecast/

JavaScript Developer

- A weather app that uses Open Weather API to display accurate weather information for up to five days, anywhere in the world.
- I developed a weather app using Open Weather API to fetch up to date weather data, jQuery to append the information to the app, and Bootstrap to create a sleek user interface.
 - Tools/Languages: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, ¡Query, Open Weather API, and Git

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

MORRIS-UNION JOINTURE COMMISSION – WARREN, NJ 2006 – 2022 **Teacher's Assistant**

G-STAR INC. LOGISTICS DEPARTMENT – SOMERSET, NJ 2005 – 2006 Assistant Manager of the distribution center in the U.S.

HOME DEPOT – BRIDGEWATER, NJ 2001 – 2005

Head Cashier